# Amir Hassanzadeh

☑ ah7557@rit.edu **६** 585-771-0680

amirhszd.github.io in linkedin.com/in/amirhassanzadeh

## SUMMARY

Scientist with five years of experience in remote sensing, signal/image processing, computer vision, machine learning and deep learning. Enjoy problem solving in collaborative and diverse teams where data scientists and software engineers work together. Available for a fulltime position in April - June 2022 timeframe.

## **EDUCATION**

Expected Graduation April - June 2022

Ph.D. in IMAGING SCIENCE

Center for Imaging Science, Rochester Institute of Technology

Thesis Title: On the Use of Imaging Spectroscopy from UAS to Model Yield and Assess Growth Stages of a Broadacre Crop

SEP 2011 -JUL 2016

**B.S. in CHEMICAL ENGINEERING** 

Faculty of Engineering, University of Guilan, Iran

Thesis Title: Numerical Simulation of Oil Extraction from Plants

#### EXPERIENCE

JUL 2021 -OCT 2021

#### **MACHINE LEARNING INTERN** · AGERpoint

Crop damage evaluation via remotely sensed data.

- Developed 5 well-documented Python packages assessing crop damage with high accuracy.
- Built an end-to-end Python pipeline for object detection (MaskRCNN) in Pytorch.
- Developed an algorithm for evaluating crop damage assessment using image classification (ResNet) of UAS data in Keras.
- · Intricately tied remote sensing libraries with (GDAL, Rasterlo, Shapely, GeoPandas) with image processing and computer vision libraries (OpenCV, Scipy, Scikit-image, Matplotlib, Pandas).
- Communicated with business clients frequently regarding their needs.
- · Collaborated frequently with other scientists in the team for brainstorming and problem-solving.

IUN 2020 -SEP 2020

#### **REMOTE SENSING INTERN** · *PrecisionHawk*

Responsible for 3 projects on semantic segmentation, lidar point cloud classification, and time series data classification using Machine Learning.

- Built and proposed a LiDAR point cloud classification model based on PointCNN in Tensorflow for segmentation of large-scale UAV point clouds (LAS), which was submitted as an ideal substitute for third-party contractors. Sped up processes in Python using scripts in C.
- Developed easy-to-use Python packages for data analysts, requiring minimal coding experience.
- Built a semantic segmentation package in Pytorch for inventory assessment in the energy section with >90% accuracy. Product helped increase the efficacy of pipelines in the data services team and automated 70-80% of manual tasks.
- Designed a video classification model (time-series data) in Pytorch (CRNN; recurrent networks) for gas leakage detection and achieved 80% accuracy.
- Took advantage of data augmentation (ImgAug) techniques to improve input training data.
- Extensively used GIS softwares including QGIS, Cloud Compare, and LAStools.
- Maintained produced packages via Git version control.

JUN 2017 -Current

#### **GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT** · Center for Imaging Science, RIT

Responsible for assessment of yield and harvest of a broad acre using imaging spectroscopy.

- · Managed and conducted UAV and ground truth data collection, data configuration, while collaborating with farmers and pilots.
- Responsible for data calibration, cleaning, preprocessing, and modelling.
- Extensively utilized GIS softwares (Envi, QGIS, Pix4D).
- · Developed and released a feature selection library for data sciences on Github in Python, including nine optimization algorithms. Library seamlessly interacts with Scikit-learn classification and regression models.
- Engineered a deep learning architecture using Memory Networks (Pytorch) for hyperspectral denoising. Conducted a benchmarking study against the state-of-the art.
- Executed a two-month greenhouse yield study from the ground-up including design of device and experiment, data collection, analysis, and conducting a report.
- Conducted a summer project on cloud height estimation using Landsat TIRS data.
- · Developed a computer vision algorithm for plant count assessment using RGB and Multispectral data with 80% accuracy. Funded by Love-beets USA.

#### **GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT** · Center for Imaging Science, RIT

- · Conducted a two-week workshop on "Deep Learning for Hyperspectral Imagery" in Advanced Environmental Applications of Remote Sensing course.
- Mentored a master's student on their capstone project.
- Held office hours, helped undergraduate students with their coding problems, and graded exams.

# **SKILLS**

- Deep Learning Frameworks: PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras
- Scientific Computing Packages: Numpy, Scipy, OpenCV, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Geopandas, Rasterlo, Shapely, GDAL, pptk, Cmake, ImgAug
- Programming (Proficient): Python
- Programming (Basic/Past): C, C++, MATLAB
- Software/others: Git, LATEX, QGIS, Cloud Compare, ENVI, ArcGIS, LAStools, Pix4D, LaTeX, Office, Photoshop, InDesign, Microsoft Office

### **PUBLICATIONS**

TBD	Hassanzadeh, A. & van Aardt, J. Hyperspectral Denoising Using Generative Adversarial Networks. Under Preparation		
TGRS	Hassanzadeh, A., Zhang, F., Murphy, S. P., Pethybridge, S. J., & van Aardt, J. (2021). Toward Crop Maturity Assessment via UAS-based Imaging Spectroscopy - A Snap Bean Pod Size Classification Field Study. <i>TGRS, Under Review</i>		
RS	Hassanzadeh, A., Zhang, F., van Aardt, J., Murphy, S. P., & Pethybridge, S. J. (2021). Broadacre crop yield estimation using imaging spectroscopy from unmanned aerial systems (UAS): A field-based case study with snap bean. <i>Remote Sensing</i> , 13(16), 3241.		
RS	Zhang, F., Hassanzadeh, A., Kikkert, J., Pethybridge, S. J., & van Aardt, J. (2021). Comparison of UAS-Based Structure-from- Motion and LiDAR for Structural Characterization of Short Broadacre Crops. <i>Remote Sensing</i> , 13(19), 3975.		
RS	Hassanzadeh, A., Murphy, S. P., Pethybridge, S. J., & van Aardt, J. (2020). Growth Stage Classification and Harvest Scheduling of Snap Bean Using Hyperspectral Sensing: A Greenhouse Study. <i>Remote Sensing</i> , 12(22), 3809.		
JARS	Hassanzadeh, A., van Aardt, J., Murphy, S. P., & Pethybridge, S. J. (2020). Yield modeling of snap bean based on hyperspectral sensing: a greenhouse study. <i>Journal of Applied Remote Sensing</i> , 14(2), 024519		

# **CONFERENCE PAPERS & TALKS**

SciPy	Hassanzadeh, A., van Aardt, J. (2021). <i>Jostar</i> : A Feature Selection Library for Data Sciences in Python. SciPy 2021 [github.com/amirhszd/jostar]
IGARSS	Hassanzadeh, A., van Aardt, J., Kikkert, J., Pethybridge, S. J., Murphy, S. P., Cross, D. (2021). Plant Counts in Dense Red Beet Crops: A Computer Vision Approach. IGARSS, 6508-6511
AGU	Hassanzadeh, A., van Aardt, J., Zhang, F., Murphy, S. P., Pethybridge, S. J. (2021). Multi-objective Wavelength Selection for Snap-bean Yield Assessment Using Remote Sensing: A Field Study. AGU Fall Meeting Abstracts, B004-0006
IGARSS	Zhang, F., <b>Hassanzadeh, A.</b> , Kikkert, J., Pethybridge, S. J., van Aardt, J. (2020). Toward a Structural Description of Row Crops Using UAS-Based LiDAR Point Clouds. IGARSS, 465-468

# **HONORS & AWARDS**

- Top third (among 20 students) in Ph.D. qualification exam.
- Top 2% (among 300,000 candidates) in undergraduate university entrance exam.
- Top student (among 90 students) in undergraduate level for three consecutive semesters.

## **PROFESSIONAL SERVICES**

•	Journal Reviewing	
	Plant Disease Journal	2021
	Field Crop Research	2021
	Journal of Applied Remote Sensing (JARS)	2021
	Journal of Open Source Software (JOSS)	2021
	Journal of Supercomputing (SUPE)	2020, 2021
•	Conference Reviewing	
	International Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium (IGARSS)	2020, 2021
	Scientific Computing with Python (SciPy)	2021